Guide to the Bert N. Corona Papers, 1923-1984
Department of Special Collections
- Subject files, 1923-1983, Series 10
  - Legal Defense and Lawyers Associations, 1942-1981, Sub-series 10.G
    - Neighborhood Legal Services, Inc., San Fernando Valley, meeting agenda, March 21, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Newsletter of the Immigration Law Panel, National Lawyers Guild, Southern California Chapter, vol. 2 nos. 1-6, 8-10, August, 1972-May, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Quiroz/Garcia deportation appeal brief, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - La Raza Law Students Association, Hastings College of the Law, San Francisco, open letter about minority admissions, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - La Raza Legal Alliance, National Conference, program, March 21-24, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Report on the Deportation and Removal of Aliens, Los Angeles County Bar Association, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Rubio, Ralph v. Superior Court of the State of California, re: resident aliens on juries, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Sleepy Lagoon case, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Sleepy Lagoon Mystery, by Guy Endore, [based on the Sleepy Lagoon Case], 1944 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Sunkist Growers, Inc., Trial Brief of Complaint Counsel before U.S. Federal Trade Commission, Docket No. 9100, February 25, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Los Tres del Barrio Case, Los Angeles, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Vallejo, Arturo, et al. v. Joseph Sureck, INS case, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Varela v. Swoap: Alien Eligibility for Public Assistance, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Western Center on Law and Poverty, Inc., workshop list, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Mexican-American issues, 1939-1983, Sub-series 10.H
    - Ante Proyecto y Borrador Para Aplicar a los Problemas de los Mexicanos Ubicados en los Estados Unidos de Norte América en el Año 1976, no author (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Articles, Mexican-American, Bilingual, and discrimination issues, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Asociación Nacional Mexico-Americana, text of speech by Maurice Travis, December 20, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - CASA, (Centro de Acción Social Autónomo), 1974-1976 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - CASA, documents and flyers, 1970-1978 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - CASA, documents, Qué es CASA?, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - CASA, history I, typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - CASA, history II, typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - CASA, issues, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - CASA, papers, flyers, misc. notes, 1973-1975 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - CASA, papers, flyers, misc. notes, 1973-1975 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - CASA, position papers and flyers, 1973-1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - CASA, resignation of Carlos Vasquez from the National Coordinating Committee, December 26, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Chicano Federation of San Diego County, Inc., Newsletter, March 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Chicano Radio Stations, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Clipping, August 1939 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, Jack Anderson and others, Mexicans in the United States, 1975, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Clippings on Mexican-American issues, in Spanish, xerox copies, 1974- 1978 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Clippings on Mexican-American issues, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Clippings on Mexican-American issues, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Clippings on Mexican-American issues, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Community Service Centers, minutes, June 6, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Conference on the Mexican and Spanish-speaking Community's Needs and Goals for the 1980s, March 24, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Conferencia Culiacan, Mexico Administrative business [1979], 1980 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Conferencia Culiacan, Mexico, Universidad Autónoma De Sinaloa: Primer Simposium Sobre Las Causas y Los Efectos de La Migración en Mexico y Los Estados Unidos, program and list of names, June 20, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Conferencia Culiacan, Mexico, Universidad Autónoma De Sinaloa: Primer Simposium Sobre Las Causas y Los Efectos de La Migración en Mexico y Los Estados Unidos, program and list of names, June 20, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Douglas Arizona Case, August 18, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Dymally, Mervyn M., Lt. Governor of California, Statement on New Immigration Policy, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - East Bay Spanish-Speaking Citizens Foundation, Inc., 1966-1970 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - El Espalda Mojada, Centro de Estudios Migratorios, A.C. Mexico, D.F., 1977 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Esterilizaciones Forzadas, news report, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Estudios Chicanos Cooperativos en Michoacan, Mexico por el Grupo de Diseño del Ante-Proyecto, March 1976 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Ground Breaking Ceremony, Kennedy Gardens, Calexico, California, funded by Rural Development Corporation, brochure, November 1, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Hermandad Mexicana Nacional, Inc., Conference on the Mexican and Spanish-Speaking Community's Needs and Goals for the 1980s, May 17, 1980,program, paste-up of program, and follow-up evaluation, March 24, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hermandad Mexicana Nacional, Inc., eviction cases, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Hermandad Mexicana Nacional, Inc., Organizing Poor People to Participate! issued by Hermandad and Western Center for Immigration Studies, National Immigration Coalition, [Guide to organizing in the community], 197? (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Hermandad Mexicana Nacional, Inc., 25th Anniversary Program, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Hermandad Mexicana Nacional, Inc., Typescripts: How to form a La Hermandad Local Chapter and Why? (2) pages; Queremos una Carta de Derechos para Trabajadores Sin Visas, (2) pages, n.d. La Hermandad Mexicana Nacional en este año de 1978, (2) pages; flyers and correspondence, 1976-1979, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Human Rights v. INS Re: Undocumented Persons, by Gilbert D. Lopez, September 1, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - The Immigration and Naturalization Laws, with special Reference to the Problems of the Mexican-American, by Sanford Jay Rosen, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Immigration scripts, Series Title: Chicano Contemporary Life, (5) b&w 8×10 photos, clippings, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Instituto el Pueblo, Program, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Inter-America Research Association, Inc., credit report on Anthony Gutierrez, President, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - MAPA, correspondence, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - MAPA resolution on undocumented aliens, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - MAPA, San Jose, programs and newsletter, 1979-1981 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - The Mexican-American, a paper prepared for the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, prepared by Helen Rowan, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - The Mexican-American and the United States, by Charles J. and Patricia L. Bustamante, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Mexican-American Social Service, Application of Aurora Lozano Mercado for immigration visa, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Mexican-American workers and economic forces, papers, flyers and clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Mexican-Americans and the Administration of Justice in the Southwest, U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, (135) pages, March 1970 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Mexican consul, clipping, December 16, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Mexican Illegal Alien Workers in the United States, by Walter Fogel, 1978? (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Mexican Migration to the United States: Causes, Consequences, and U.S. Responses, by Wayne A. Cornelius, Cambridge, MIT, (Monograph Series of the Migration and Development Study Group) to be published July 1978 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Mexico-Congreso Del Trabajo, statement and (2) cassette tapes of resolutions, 1978? (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - National Chicano Forum, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Newsletter, Chicano Federation of San Diego County, Inc., January 1977 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - El Otro Lado, Una Guia Para Los Indocumentados, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Our Badge of Infamy, A Petition to the United Nations on the Treatment of the Mexican Immigrant, by American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, (1) copy in English, (2) copies in Spanish, April 1959 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Petition to the United Nations accusing the U.S. government of genocide against non-Anglo groups, n.d.,News release by the Congress of Mexican-American Unity, November 21, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Proceso de Aculturación de los Inmigrantes Mexicanos en los Estados Unidos Mexicanos, by Sin. Culiacan, Anteproyecto de Investigación, (17) pages, April 11, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Proposal Working Paper for Leadership and Unity Youth and Student Conferences for Los Angeles Mexican/Latino Youth, Meeting with Parents Involved in Community Action (PICA); Los Angeles Commission of Human Relations and the Conference Coalition of the Mexican and Spanish-Speaking Community: Needs and Goals for the 1980s, (10) pages, September 24, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Puntos Basicos que Se Deben Saber Sobre Los Estados Unidos, by Cisco Drake, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Salt of the Earth, film about Mexican-American workers in New Mexico, review and law suit, 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - San Francisco Mission College, Chicano/Hispanic Awareness Committee, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - San Juan Macias, invitation to a talk at the Center, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Shame of a Nation: A Documented Story of Police State Terror Against Mexican-Americans in the U.S.A., no author, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Southwest Council of La Raza, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Southwind: The Mexican Migration, by Richard Louv, A Series for the San Diego Union, pamphlet, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Spanish-Speaking Media, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Spanish-Speaking Media, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Step-Children of a Nation: The Status of Mexican-Americans, by Isabel Gonzalez, American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Temporary Mexican Worker's Act, S.1427, June 1979 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - The Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo of 1848, H.R. 9422, A bill to enforce it, June 24, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Valley of Tears/Magic Valley, prospectus for a film, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Zoot Suit [the play], flyers and papers, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Nacozari Mine Strike, 1973-1979, Sub-series 10.I
    - Clippings and flyers, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and papers, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Clippings and papers, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - El Comité Apoyo Mineros de Nicozari, Plan de Organización Para, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union support for Nacozari Strike, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Nacozari Committee, L.A. Area, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Nacozari, History of the Movement, (in Spanish) 1975-1979 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Nacozari Texas Committee, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Who is American Smelting and Refining Co.? (ASARCO), ca. 1973 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Peace Organizations, 1974-1981, Sub-series 10.J
    - Peace and Justice newsletter, Peace Action Council, Los Angeles, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Peace organizations, newsletters and flyers, 1974, 1975, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - World Peace Council, Documents and Journals, 1975-1976, 1978, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Political theory, 1970-1976, Sub-series 10.K
    - The American Journey, typescript by Joe Holland with Mary Burke and William Ryan, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Articles on economic issues, 1973-1975 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Lenin: Imperialism, the Highest Stage of Capitalism, a Popular Outline, published by Progress Publishers, Moscow, 1970,(1) copy in English, (1) copy in Spanish; articles on labor issues (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Marxist Analysis of Labor and Immigration, ca. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Marxist Social Science: Bibliographic Essay, by Rudy Torres, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Papers on the International Model, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - La Politica de Emigración, del Partido Comunista de España, documentos, 1970s (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Revisionists: articles on Communism, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Socialism and Communism, article, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Prison issues, 1967-1975, Sub-series 10.L
    - Attica Memorial Book, Fighting Back! 1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Francesca García Case Statement of Juanita García, daughter of Francesco García, May 19, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - In re: Paul L. Gault, et al., Reprint from U.S. Supreme Court Reports, 18L ed 2d 527, 87 S Ct, Argued December 16, 1966,Decided May 15, 1967.[A 15 year old boy committed as a juvenile delinquent to the Arizona State Industrial School for the period of his minority, after the boy was taken into custody alledgedly without notice to his parents. Also information on San Quentin inmates. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Information on Mexican-Americans in prison and legal defenses, San Quentin, ca. 1967-1973 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Letters from prisoners, 1967-1975 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Soledad Prison, letter from Mrs. Rosalie Souza, wife of Martin G. Souza, regarding her husband's plight in Vacaville Penitentiary, January 1970 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Student Papers, 1967-1979, Sub-series 10.M
    - Book Reviews, A-N, (16) papers (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Book Reviews, O-Z, (25) papers (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Final Examinations, CS430, 1975, (9) papers (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Final Examinations, CS430, 1976, (18) papers (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Final Examinations, CS430, 1979, (10) papers (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Final Examinations, CS430, 1979, (6) papers (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Final Examinations, CS111B, 1967, (1) paper (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Student Cassette Tapes, (2) tapes with (1) paper, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Term Papers, A-Chicano P, (11) papers (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Term Papers, Chicano P-Fa, (13) papers (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Term Papers, Fo-Immigration An, (10) papers (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Term Papers, Immigration As-N, (16) papers (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Term Papers, O-T, (16) papers (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Term Papers, U-Z, (8) papers (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Term Papers, untitled, (5) papers (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - United States Political Campaigns and Issues, 1962-1979, Sub-series 10.N
    - Conference of Democratic Spanish-Speaking Elected Officials, November 2, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Tom Hayden campaign, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Eugene McCarthy Campaign, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Eugene McCarthy Campaign, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Muñoz, Rosalio, literature on campaign for supervisor, 3rd District, Los Angeles County, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - National issues, newsletters, flyers and clippings, includes: Carter Campaign material, 1976;Network, December, 1978, Spring, June, 1979;Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, (3) issues, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Registrar of Voters, January 6, 1969and Active Deputies, January 31, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Report of Registration, State of California, by March Fong Eu, Secretary of State 1978;(15) decals and (5) buttons that say: VOTE Register by Mail - Regístrese por Correo, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Newsletter and flyers, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Voter Registration, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Urban Problems, 1966-1980, Sub-series 10.O
    - Citizens' Commission on Police Repression, Los Angeles, newsletter, October 1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Community Services Organization, 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Greater Los Angeles Urban Coalition, 1970, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Housing Code Enforcement and Rehabilitation, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Police Crisis, Clippings, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Police Crisis, Clippings, 1971-1975 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Police Crisis, Flyers, press releases and letters to the editor, 1970-1972 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Police Crisis, Papers, 1967-1972 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Women, 1971-1983, Sub-series 10.P
    - A La Mujer, by Ricardo Flores Magon, Spanish and English, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Luisa Moreno Bemis, articles and biography, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Chicanas in history, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Chicanas y Mexicanas, articles on the women's movement, and women's issues, ca. 1971-1975 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Los Efectos de la Inmigración en la Vida de la Mujer Mexicana, by Dolores Delgado Cambell, presented at the Primer Simposium Sobre las Causas y los Efectos de la Migración de Mexico y los E.U., 1980? (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Gonzalez, Lila G., New Voices in Raza Literature, (34) pages, ca. 1980? (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - International Year of the Woman: La Mujer Mexicana-Chicana Como Política en Nuestra Historia, Mexico City, 197? (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Mexican-American Women's National Association, (MANA) membership brochure, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Minorities and Women in Television, Window Dressing on the Set: an Update, a report of the United States Commission on Civil Rights, January 1979 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Ortega, Margarita Ortega, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Parsons, Lucy E. Gonzalez Parsons, Chicano Studies 430, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Progressive Women's Organization, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Remarkable American Women, Life Magazine, Special Report, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Student papers, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Tenayuca, Emma, xerox of her story in The Texas Observer, October 28, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Tenayuca: Emma Tenayuca, by Alfonso Torres-Salas, Chicano Studies 430, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Urrea, Teresita Urrea, La Santa de Cabora, by Mario Gill, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - The Woman Question, (8) page manuscript, no author, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Women and Revolution, Journal of the Women's Commission of the Spartacist League, Spring, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Women for Legislative Action, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Women Union Organizers in Mexico and the United States, clippings and stories, 1976-1980 (Box 39, Folder 16)
- Alphabetical files, 1946-1984, Series 11
  This series contains clippings, correspondence, and other subject matter arranged alphabetically by individual, subject, or organization.
  - Acevedo, Elias (Alex), clipping, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Affirmative Action, Weber Case, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - ALBA, Southern California Cooperation Community, Accounts paid, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - ALBA, Southern California Cooperation Community, Accounts payable, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - ALBA, Southern California Cooperation Community, Accounts receivable, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - ALBA, Southern California Cooperation Community, invoices, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - All-Brite Electric Cases, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, New York, press release, flyers, 1974, 1976, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Immigration Proposal, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - American Mexican Rodeo, poster, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - American Red Cross, donation receipt, December 18, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Annenberg School of Communications, USC seminar, Media for Impact, brochure, November 8, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Banquet '78, see Series: Writings of Bert Corona (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Banquet '79 - A Salute to Labor, 29th annual affair honoring outstanding defenders of civil rights, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Banquet '80 - Freedom is a Constant Struggle, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Becerril, Maria de la Paz, clippings and correspondence, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Bilingual-Bicultural Education, Toward Meaningful and Equal Educational Opportunity, Public Hearings report by the Special Subcommittee on Bilingual-Bicultural Education of the California State Assembly, July 1976 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Bilingual Education, articles, 1970s (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Bilingual Education Services, Inc., October 11, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Bilingual Education Services, Inc., reception area purchase receipts, 1976-1977 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Bilingual Education, Statement by Ernesto Galarza, June 3, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - John Birch Society, clipping, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Bisbee '17 by Robert Houston, book review, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Bound for Glory, flyer for film about Woodie Guthrie, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Brazil Trip, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - The Brotherhood of Priestly Revolutionairies, by Father Blase Bonpane on Father Camilo Torres, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - El Calendario Chicano, 1974, 1976[1976 calendar is oversize, in box # 54] (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - California Coalition of Hispanic Organizations, Bylaws, correspondence, clippings, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - California Coalition of Hispanic Organizations, Bylaws, correspondence, clippings, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - California Newsreel, film catalog, ca. 1979 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - California State Legislators, list, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - California State University, Los Angeles, Grading practices and grade inflation, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - California State University, Los Angeles, Grants, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - California Unemployment Insurance, 1973, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - California's Blueprint for National Welfare Reform: Proposals for the Nation's Food Stamp and Aid to Families with Dependent Children Programs, September 1974 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Calo-Pachucos, Bato-Locos, Manuscript, by Salvador Ramirez, Jesus Granado, Jr., Francisco Padilla, Aurora O. Martinez, (177) pages, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Campaign for Human Development, pre-application for grants, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Cantu, Mario, legal defense, accused of conspiracy to conceal illegal aliens, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Cantu, Mario, San Antonio case, statement and clippings, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Carter, Jimmy, flyer, 1982? (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Casa Amaya, residential program at Colorado State University, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Committee on Urban Ministry, Conference, Estes Park, Colorado, October 12-16, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Census Bureau Litigation and Legislation Status Report November 14, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Census, State of Georgia, population by counties, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Census, survey questions to validate uncounted persons in tracts dominated by Spanish surnames, and Were you Counted? 1980 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Center for Western Hemispheric Studies, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Centro Libre De Experimentación Teatral y Artística (CLETA), reviews, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - CETA, (Comprehensive Employment and Training Act, A Citizen's Action Guide), March 1976 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - CETA, Public Employment and Education Center, Crecer y Florecer, [newsletter], Los Angeles, February 1980 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - CETA, time sheets for 7th Step Foundation, Inc., from Western Center for Immigration Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Chargin, Judge Gerald S., Superior Court of California, Juvenile Division, Statements of the Court, [case of judicial abuse], September, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Chavez, Cesar, flyers and clippings about the United Farm Workers, 1973-1975, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Chavez, Cesar, in Mexico, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Chavez, Cesar, letter to the editor, Los Angeles Times, March 28, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Chavez, Cezar, Rejects Carter's Immigration Proposals, United Farm Workers of America, AFL-CIO Third Consitutional Convention, Fresno, California, August 26-28, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Chavez, Cesar, The Rhetorical Worlds of Cesar Chavez and Reies Tijerina, by John C. Hammerback, and Richard J. Jensen, in Western Journal of Speech Communication, Summer, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 18)